# Maeva Ralafiarindaza

#### **DATA SCIENTIST**

maevadevs@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/maevaralafiarindaza github.com/maevadevs

### **ABOUT**

Highly motivated and experienced Data Analyst moving into the field of Data Science and Machine Learning. My passion is working with data technology and logic to ask the right questions, seek answers to critical questions, figure out solutions to problems, and empower others in their work. I am looking forward to applying my data and technological skills in solving problems and further growing my skill sets.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Python (SciPy, Pandas, Streamlit, Geopandas, Jupyter, Flask)
- R (Tidyverse, Shiny, RStudio)
- SQL (PostgreSQL, SQL Server, MySQL)
- Machine Learning (Supervised, Unsupervised, NLP)
- NoSQL (Neo4j, MongoDB, Redis)
- Web Programming (HTML/CSS, Typescript, NodeJS, React)
- Project Management (Kanban, Smartsheet, Visio)
- Cloud Systems (Azure, AWS, Heroku)
- Spreadsheet (MS Excel, Google Sheet)
- Collaboration Systems (Github, Kaggle, Colab, Slack)

## SOFT SKILLS

- Critical Thinking
- Problem-Solving
- Logical Reasoning
- Teamwork
- Public Speaking
- Communication
- Training / Coaching
- Self-Guided Learning

### **EDUCATION**

### **BOOTCAMP, DATA SCIENCE**

2021 | Nashville Software School, Nashville, TN

#### **MASTER OF SCIENCE, INFORMATION SECURITY**

2014 | Lipscomb University, Nashville, TN

# BACHELOR OF BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION, IT MANAGEMENT

2012 | Lipscomb University, Nashville, TN

### **BOOTCAMP HIGHLIGHTS**

### WHAT'S IN THE NEWS (Capstone Project)

- Solo NLP project. Analyzed news articles in order to predict the categories of unlabeled articles and to generate short summaries. I developed a Streamlit+Flask Web Application using Azure and AWS, plus an accompanying Google Chrome extension as the final minimum viable product.
- Google Site: <a href="https://sites.google.com/view/whatsinthenews">https://sites.google.com/view/whatsinthenews</a>
- Repository:
  - https://github.com/maevadevs/Whats-In-The-News

#### **PROJECT COVFLU** (Midcourse Project)

- Solo project. Created a R-Shiny dashboard application that features a data-based comparison between the effects of Covid-19 in 2020 and Influenza in 2019 on the basis of the U.S. cases demographics.
- Shiny App: maevadevs.shinyapps.io/Project CovFlu
- Repository: github.com/maevadevs/project-covflu

## **BOOTCAMP HIGHLIGHTS (Cont.)**

#### **NASHVILLE HEALTHCARE PROVIDERS**

- Teamwork project with 16 data scientist apprentices. Leveraged the 2017 Hop Teaming dataset of Medicare referral claims to examine how Medicare patients move through the intricate and complicated Middle Tennessee healthcare system.
- Google Site:
  - https://sites.google.com/view/nashvilleprovidersds4
- Repository: https://github.com/maevadevs/hcbb-hop-team

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### DATA SCIENTIST APPRENTICE | Sep 2020 - June 2021 Nashville Software School

NSS is a technical school that provides a 9-months intensive learning program in technical, visual, math, and storytelling skills for Data Science through practical application and hands-on projects.

- Developed technical skills needed for data science projects with SQL, Python, R, Math, Big Data, Machine Learning.
- Developed soft-skills that data scientists need on a daily basis: Critical Thinking, Teamwork, Communication, Project Management, Problem-Solving, Research, Public Speaking.
- Applied newly learned skills with hands-on applications on real-word projects over multiple domain-knowledge.
- Built and delivered data science deliverables in a timely fashion.
- Class Website: https://nss-data-science-cohort-4.github.io

# DATA ANALYST | Oct 2020 - Present Promises Behavioral Health

PBH is a nationwide healthcare provider headquartered in Brentwood, TN that provides treatment programs related to mental health, addiction disorder, eating disorder, and trauma.

- Hands-on analysis and reporting on medical, operational, and financial data from EMR, CRM, and RCM systems.
- Provide data-based insights on various business process improvements and use-case scenarios.
- Contribute in the development and enhancement of data infrastructures, data pipelines, and data project deliverables.
- Teamwork with the IT team and overall staff on different data-related projects.

## IT & MEDIA TRAINER | June 2012 - Oct 2020 Healing Hands International

HHI is a mission-focused Non-profit organization that provides material aid and spiritual empowerment around the world.

- Oversaw all data systems and data security.
- Analyzed financial data using SQL, Excel, Access.
- Produced financial reports and visuals for decision makers.
- Generated textual and visual documentations.
- Implemented project analysis and transition of IT infrastructures to Cloud-based systems.
- Trained and assisted staff in the use of technological assets.